新疆·和田
Xin jiang, he tian
走在夜市里面
In night market
不知道该吃哪一个
Cant decide what to eat
这家比较好吃
This one looks not bad
吃过吗
Have you eaten this before?
对
Yeah
多少钱一个
How much it is?
5块
Five yuan
这个都怎么加
What I can add?
5元的 加酸奶 加蜜
Five yuan for yogurt and honey
加糖是吧
Add sugar right?
那我要一个这个的 5块钱的
I want to buy that one for 5 yuan
对 打包
Yeah, take out
这是刨冰
This is shaved ass
怪不得我说 拿的时候是凉的
I see why it is cold
看到吗 这是粽子
This is “Zong Zi”(glutinous rice stuffed with different fillings and wrapped in bamboo leaves)
加了酸奶
They added yogurt in it
哇 浓稠的老酸奶的味道
Very classic flavor
就你吃的时候 可以根据
You can decide
自己喜不喜欢吃糖
To add moderate amount
着重自己加 自己调（甜味）
Of sugar
有种吃冰淇淋的感觉
It taste like ice cream
虽然说这边有这么多小吃
Even though there are so many snacks here
但是前面有10多个摊位
There still about 10 booths
都在卖一种东西 就是
Sale for same snacks
蒸蛋 煮蛋 煎蛋我们很常见
Steamed egg, boiled egg and fried egg is common to us
但是 烤蛋是什么样的味道呢
But how grilled egg taste like?
今天 跟着我去看一看吧
Follow me and how it looks like
在新疆 烤的东西很多
Grilled food is very commonly in Xinjiang
像烤全羊 烤鱼
Like grilled whole lamb and grilled fish
我们都吃过
We eaten both before
但是这个烤蛋 着实让我觉得好奇
I’m very curious what it is
这个最大的是 什么
What’s that biggest egg?
鸵鸟蛋
Ostrich egg
点的最多的是什么蛋
What
最多的是
The most order is
会放鸽子蛋 野鸡蛋 土鸡蛋
We have pigeon egg, and two type of eggs
在放上蜂蜜 藏红花 玛咖
Add honey, saffron, MaJa()
弄的半生半熟的
Half cooked
半生半熟的状态
吃全熟的也行
Well down is okay
就是你说的 三蛋一星
来一个吗
Want one?
对
Yeah
她是 要先（在蛋上）弄一个孔
She drilled a hole on the egg first
这啥蛋 这是
What kind of egg it is?
鸵鸟蛋
Ostrich egg
这个鸵鸟蛋 280块钱一个
This Ostrich egg is 280 yuan for each
280块钱
280 yuan
我们以前吃300块钱一个
That was 300 yuan before
这个大约烤多久
How long it will cook?
5分钟
Five minutes
（5分钟达到）半熟的一个状态
它这个鸡蛋也可以这么烤着吃
冒泡了
It is bubbled
鸡蛋是多少钱一个
How much for a chicks egg?
鸡蛋 鸡蛋是几块钱一个
鸡蛋一个两块五毛钱
2.5 yuan for each
那个呢
How about that?
这个 一共多少钱
How much total?
这个 一个50块钱
50 yuan for each
就是 它是好几个蛋放在一起的
It is a combo with different eggs
鹅蛋10元/个      x1  goose egg 10 yuan
鸽子蛋10元/个  x2  pigeon egg  10 yuan
土鸡蛋5元/个    x1 free range egg 5 yuan
普通鸡蛋2.5元/个 x1  regular egg 2.5 yuan
鹅蛋10元/个      x1
鸽子蛋10元/个  x2
土鸡蛋5元/个    x1
普通鸡蛋2.5元/个 x1
一个鹅蛋 一个鸡蛋 一个鸽子蛋对不对
两个鸽子蛋
Two pigeon eggs
还有一个土鸡蛋
And a free range egg
我们要尝一尝
We gonna try it
一个50块钱的烤蛋是什么样的味道
How 50 yuan grilled egg taste like?
都看不到了
I cant see
我来剖析一下这个味道
Let me explain the taste
首先你吃到的是甜味
You taste sweet at first
是烤 有点焦的这种蜂蜜的甜味
It is sugar from honey
然后呢就是 蛋黄很细腻
And yolk is very smooth
吃起来 真的很像烤地瓜的瓤
Texture is very similar as grilled sweet potato
那边在表演节目 这边会有一些吵
There is a little noisy cuz they have a show
这个蛋之所以这么贵 是因为里面
This egg is expensive because
混合了很多的蛋
There is a lot eggs mix up
最外面是鹅蛋
Outermost is goose egg
里面还加了两个鸽子蛋 还有一个土鸡蛋
And they add two pigeon egg and a free-range egg
一个野鸡蛋
A
就是这么着一个50块钱的综合蛋
50 yuan total
虽然说 各个蛋加起来是37块5
Although totally price of each egg is 37.5 yuan
但是里面还加了蜂蜜 加了藏红花
Because they add honey and saffron
其它的调味料
And other spices
在做的过程当中 会给你放一些调料品
They add some spices during cook
但是如果说 你觉得
But if you think
味道不太符合你的口味
Flavor not as you expect
她这边会摆放一些的调味料
She had some spices by side
你 可以自己加一些
You can add some spices by yourself
咱们吃的烤蛋 她是在上面弄了一个孔
They drilled a hole on my grilled egg
放在炭火上烤
Grilled it on fire
还有一种就是直接
And another type is put egg
皮也不用去 放进里面烤
On  fire without do anything
看这个就是没有敲掉它蛋皮的
See, this egg didn’t take of shell
烤蛋
Grilled egg
晶莹剔透的 很可爱
Crystal clear very cute
我以为一个50块钱的烤蛋已经很贵了
I thought 50 yuan grilled egg is expensive
但是前面坐的这个小哥
But the bro who sit front of us
一下子要了10个 500块钱的
He ordered 1o eggs which is 500 yuan
现在还坐在后面 等着他的烤蛋呢
He still wait for his eggs
关 注
雪 鱼 探 店